Youngwook Jung

✓ yj10@illinois.edu | • +1.217.377.1239 | • Website | in LinkedIn

SUMMARY

As a Ph.D. candidate in Economics at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, my research focuses on labor economics, particularly internal migration, retirement, and demographic economics. In my primary research, I investigate how the influx of prime-age workers impacts marginal retirement-age workers in an area. I have extensive experience with causal inference and a keen interest in a broad range of socioeconomic topics. I thrive in interdisciplinary environments and actively seek opportunities to collaborate with others.

EDUCATION

2017–present Ph.D. Econo	mics at University of Illinois	at Urbana-Champaign (UIUC)
--------------------------	--------------------------------	----------------------------

2015–2017 M.A. Economics at Sungkyunkwan University, Republic of Korea 2009–2015 B.A. Economics at Sungkyunkwan University, Republic of Korea

RESEARCH FIELDS AND TOPICS

Labor and demographic economics; Internal migration, retirement, firms, housing market

Research Papers

❖ Substitutability between prime-age and marginal retirement-age workers (Job Market Paper) This study examines the substitutability between prime-age workers, aged 25–54, and marginal retirement-age workers, aged 55–64. It investigates the impact on the cohort of older workers when younger workers flow into an area and estimates the elasticity of substitution between the two cohorts. This research employs the use of instrumental variable and local projection techniques to establish robust causal inferences.

Work in Progress

- ❖ Differential response of young and mature firms to labor demand shocks
- ❖ Negative net migration and the local economy (with Geoffrey J.D. Hewings)
- ❖ Is this time really different? Impacts of COVID-19 on state and local economies and housing markets (with Jiyoung Chae, Ivan Caceres, and Geoffrey J.D. Hewings)
- ❖ Higher house prices rob the poor's leisure time
- ❖ Assessing the validity of fiscal contract theory: An examination of adopting value-added tax

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

2019–2021 Regional Economics Application Laboratory: Research assistant to Prof. Geoffrey Hewings

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant

Fall 2023-present Big Data Analytics in Finance, *Prof. Gao Xing* Fall 2022-Spring 2023 Macroeconomic Principles, *Prof. Vazquez Jose*

Spring 2022 Macroeconomic Principles, Prof. Ramses Armendariz Buaun

Fall 2016 Statistical Analysis for Economics, Prof. In-Moo Kim

Spring 2016 Mathematical Statistics (Graduate course), Prof. In-Moo Kim

Fellowships and Awards

2023	Travel Award, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign
2017 - 2018	Department Fellowship, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign
2016	The National Research Scholarship (Humanities and Social Sciences), funded by Korea Stu-
	dent Aid Foundation (2016-9012054987) for promising research projects in the social sciences
2014 – 2015	Cho Byeongdu Scholarship, granted by Cho, CEO of Dongju Co., for undergraduate students
	who demonstrate leadership and outstanding academic achievement
2014	Excellence Award, Undergraduate Paper Competition, hosted by Sungkyunkwan University
2013	Excellence Award, International Development Competition, hosted by Korea Export-Import
	Bank
2013	Special Award, Thesis Competition, hosted by Market Economic Research Institute
2012	Best Prize, Thesis Competition, hosted by Korea Development Institute
2010	Best Research Paper, academic conference, hosted by Sungkyunkwan University

SKILLS

Computational Stata, R (advanced), Python, SQL Languages English (fluent), Korean (native)

ACTIVITIES AND COMMUNITIES

Dasan Finance Club (served as a chief seminar organizer) in SKKU Military Service (Sergeant, Republic of Korea Air Force)

REFERENCES

Professor Greg Howard (Chair) Professor Geoffrey J.D. Hewings

glhoward@illinois.edu hewings@illinois.edu

Professor Stephen L. Parente Professor Alexander W. Bartik

UIUC, Department of Economics UIUC, Department of Economics

parente@illinois.edu abartik@illinois.edu

Last updated: May 3, 2023